UNDER CONSTRUCTION

Scott Hale, CPA

CAREER PROFILE

Energetic, driven leader possessing critical thinking and problem solving skills developed as a CPA in public accounting. Effective communicator with experience in team, one on one, and group presentation settings. Developed appreciation for diverse business firms and corporate cultures through experience in public accounting, industry and business school.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF NORTH TEXAS, SCHOOL OF BUSINESS, Denton, TX

Bachelors in Accounting/Masters in Accounting: Entrepreneurial Perspectives

December, 2013

EXPERIENCE

Grant Thornton LLP Jan 2013 - 2017

The seventh largest accounting network in the world by combined fee income. Grant Thornton LLP is the sixth largest U.S. accounting and advisory organization.

Senior Audit Associate

- Ran client engagements from start to finish, which includes planning, executing, directing, and completing financial audits and managing to budget.
- Supervised, trained, and mentored associates and interns on audit process and assess performance of staff for engagement reviews; perform in-charge role as needed.
- Worked with audit team to identify and resolve client issues discovered during audit process.
- Researched and analyzed financial statements and audit- and tax-related issues utilizing electronic databases, and employed audit software to review and compile financial information.
- Maintained a good working relationship with clients to enhance customer satisfaction and worked with client management and staff at all levels to perform audit services.
- Proactively interacted with key client management to gather information, resolve audit-related problems, and make recommendations for business and process improvements.
- Gained comprehensive understanding of client operations, processes, and business objectives and utilized that knowledge
 on engagements. Audited many different types of companies including: Oil and Gas, Food and Beverage, Retail,
 Technology, and Higher Education.

Audit Associate

- Reviewed and audited business transaction cycles including cash, treasury, capital expenditures, and other income and expenses.
- Researched audit issues, utilizing electronic databases, and review-tracking financial information, utilizing audit related software. Identifying, researching, assessing, and informing senior staff members of audit related issues.
- Worked with client team members to build rapport and strong client relationships.

Audit Intern

Gained a comprehensive understanding of assigned client operations, processes and business objectives, and then utilized
that knowledge on assigned engagements. Evaluated and tested IT and business processes and controls and identify areas
of risk.

SUN MOUNTAIN INTERNATIONAL, Quito, Ecuador

August 2011- 2012

Sun Mountain International (SMTN) is both a US and Ecuador-based socio-economic development organization

Administration Assistant

- Helped with budgeting for USAID projects
- Worked directly with programmers to help develop and organize the company's website for further outreach.
- Learned Spanish through immersion and through collaboration projects with native employees.

Freelancer - Contractor 2017 - Present

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Certifications: Certified Public Accountant, State of Texas (obtained license in 2013)

Technical Skills: Extensive experience in Microsoft programs (Windows, Excel, Word, Access, PowerPoint). Significant

experience using IDEA Data Extraction Software